- Where?
- There.
What's that idiot doing?
- Teacher!
- Onitchi!
Hey, get up!
Onitchi!
Hey! I'm the one about
to die here!
Just what were you thinking,
Noboru?
C'mon, Noboru!
Say something, will ya!
Noboru... he's always
been teased in our class.
It's because he's always
so timid,
it makes you want
to tease him.
You guys...
Hey, are you alright?
My Benz!
Who'd do something
so terrible!
I don't want to go, teacher.
Quiet! Hey, Noboru,
wait a sec.
Yikes!
But what a night!
Last night he jumped
from the roof.
And he said he wouldn't go
to school today.
I had to drag him!
Do you mean...
- You... this car...
- Huh, oh yes...
Uh no, I mean...
It went bam!
I don't know who's it is,
but it sure saved us.
Please thank, whoever's it is.
- It went bam?
- Hey Noboru, let's go.
This weekend on the trip
to the onsen with my family...
I was going to show it to
them for the first time.
It was supposed to be
a surprise.
I left it here for that!
I haven't driven it even 10 km!
And...
there's still 48 loan payments
left on it!
Morning!
Wasn't Noboru fun yesterday!
Yeah! Miyabi, you really
pulled down his pants.
Yeah, yeah! And he was
about this big!
Are you a baby?
I don't think he'll come today.
That garbage.
Take your seats.
Yesterday...
Noboru,
jumped from this roof.
Apparently,
it was because someone from
class was bullying him.
Whoever did, come on
and apologize right now.
One of your friends from class
tried to kill himself!
This is the least you could do!
We haven't been bullying
anyone!
We all get along, teacher.
If you don't believe us,
then ask Noboru.
Did we do anything we
have to apologize for?
Well, Noboru?
If there's anything you want
to say, just say it!
I...
No one bullied me.
It's too early for this silliness.
I wish you wouldn't accuse us
of these kind of things.
SORIMACHI TAKASHI
MATSUSHIMA NANAKO
KONDÔ YOSHIMASA
ENJÔJI AYA
NUMATA BAKU
KOBAYASHI MASAHIRO
IDA KUNIHIKO
KIRARI
IKEUCHI HIROYUKI
YAMAZAKI YÛTA
TOKUYAMA HIDENORI
KUBOZUKA YÔSUKE
NAKAMURA AIMI
KURODA MIKI
OGURI SHUN
FUJIKI NAOHITO
MABUCHI ERIKA
TATEISHI RYÔKO
NAKAO AKIRA
SHIRAKAWA YUMI
English Subtitles by
STUDIO NEW MEDIA
Subtitles Edited and Timed by
SCHWEFELHEXAFLUORID
D-ADDICTS
www.d-addicts.com
Directed by
NAKAJIMA SATORU
A Production of
KANSAI TEREBI & AVEC
- Good morning!
- Morning.
Yo.
Hey! Hey! Fuyutsuki-sensei,
what about mine?
If you want some,
then get it yourself.
Man, is she still upset
about those pictures...
What are you doing?
You shouldn't sneak into here!
- What?
- Not "what"!
What are you saying!
He's trespassing,
shall I chase him out?
Don't be stupid!
That's Fujitomi-sensei from
Classic Literature.
But...
I've never seen him before!
Of course not.
This is the first month you're
at school, right?
I'm sorry.
We're you sick?
Well...
yes...
I guess you could say
he was sick.
Stress, depression,
chronic fatigue, heart condition,
and high blood pressure.
Fujitomi-sensei let's
the students
and parents get too him
too easily.
He's brings it upon himself.
- Good morning.
Fujitomi-sensei, good morning.
Good morning.
Well, you come to school
for your salary.
You know, this is almost
salary robbery, isn't it?
That's going too far.
But it is a problem, it's affecting
the quality of instruction.
The students suffer.
We'd like people to really
consider how well you can fulfill
the obligations of teaching.
In any occupation,
people should be aware
of their duties.
It shouldn't be any different
at a school.
Right, Fuyutsuki-sensei?
- Well...
- Exactly, sir.
When it comes to that, it's best
if the person would take
it upon themselves to quit.
Now, now.
I see there's bullying
even among teachers.
Hey, you! Don't by silly!
Are you saying we're
a school of demons?
How rude!
C'mon, tell 'em off!
Well said, sir!
Just when is this academy
going to return to normal?
Geeze! If there's something
they want to say,
they should come out
and say it!
Hey! You too!
If you want to say something,
- you should say it!
- I'm sorry.
It's because you take it quietly
- that they take advantage of you!
- Sorry.
You haven't done
anything wrong,
- don't apologize!
- I'm sorry.
C'mon, are you listening?
For crying out loud...
GARBAGE
This garbage pail's
pretty useless.
He can't do anything without
Onizuka.
He should have gone and died
from jumping from the roof.
He was probably just faking it.
He doesn't have the guts
to do that.
That garbage!
Throw it
Looks like you guys have been
pretty friendly
with Onizuka lately.
What's wrong? Do it!
Excuse me,
this is dangerous.
Um, if this is garbage,
then I'll throw it away.
I'm sorry.
HEALTH ROOM
Um, what are you doing?
Onitchi, c'mon!
The story of Isezakichô,
Yokohama.
There was a rumor of bentô
of shûmai
made with cadaver meat.
One man was about to eat
one of the shûmai bentô
he bought from that place.
And then...
Even though no one
was around,
"Don't eat it," he heard.
It startled him and he looked
around, but there was no one.
He started thinking...
He opened his bentô.
Could it be coming
from the shûmai?
The man looked around
once more,
he looked at his bentô.
That's when he saw...
It was stuck to the lid, right?
Hey!
What? Is that all?
It was just shûmai!
That wasn't scary at all!
That's because he spoiled it!
Everyone knows that story
already.
Hey you!
Then why don't you come up
with something better?
No, I'd rather...
C'mon, do it, you messed
mine up...
Okay then, here goes...
This is my own story.
This is the story of a father
who killed his own baby.
Sorry.
This father...
had a newborn baby.
He had no choice,
and abandoned
the baby in a coin locker.
That was his downfall.
The father couldn't stand
the guilt.
He returned to the coin locker.
But...
When he opened the door...
The baby that should have
been there was gone.
He was probably just stuck
to the back of the door, right?
Sorry.
Five years passed.
As if pulled by fate,
he returned to that coin locker.
That's when...
A boy so pale he was almost
transparent,
was looking at him.
The man asked,
where did you come from?
That boy answered like this...
"I... was born here."
The man gathered his courage,
and asked...
"Who is your father?"
And then that boy
answered him...
"It's you!"
Hey, don't look! I'm scared!
You're really good!
When you tell it,
it seems so real!
C'mon, tell us one more!
Okay, this is the one about
the man who goes
into the toilet every night
with a saw.
What are you doing!
Class has started!
Oh no!
Run!
Wait you! Just what do you
think you're doing!
Sorry about that!
Noboru's ghost story telling
was so scary, I lost track of time.
So then...
where were we today?
- Page 100.
- Oh okay, page 100.
Goodbye!
I see.
You're giving the director
your resignation?
That's too bad.
I had such high hopes for you,
Fujitomi-sensei.
I'm sorry to hear that.
So Nakamaru-sensei, we should
have a farewell party.
Yes, we should.
- Fuyutsuki-sensei.
- Yes?
Could you reserve us
a room at the restaurant?
And could you take up
a collection
from everyone, 3,000 yen
should be enough.
You want me to?
Of course?
Who else would I be asking?
- Yes.
- Oh, sir! About your car...
Oh yes...
I'm sorry to cause so much
trouble.
Not at all!
So... are you really quitting?
My parents run a ryokan.
I'm going to go help them.
I felt I could do this for my
family's livelihood,
and tried my best.
But it looks like it's too
much for me.
Fuyutsuki-sensei,
here's my 3,000 yen.
- Thanks.
- Shall I help you?
- No, that's okay...
- I could...
- Fuyutsuki-sensei.
- Yes?
- My 3,000 yen.
- Thank you very much.
- Please get everyone else's.
- Yes.
- Kitano-sensei.
- Yes? What is it?
I'm taking up a collection for
Fujitomi-sensei's
retirement party, could you
contribute 3,000 yen?
What? And this month's
budget is tight...
Here you go, 3,000 yen.
Okay, thank you very much.
Why the heck do I always get
stuck doing these things...
Better not.
Lucky! What's going
to be for dinner tonight!
What are you scheming
with Onizuka?
Are you going to get him
to be your bodyguard?
We'll take good care
of you today!
Hey you! Come back here!
Oh no, I have to do
something now...
Don't take us for granted!
You should have died.
Nobody cares if you're alive.
Shall we kill you?
Drop dead, Noboru!
You girls! What are you doing!
What do you think you're
doing here!
It's a game.
A game?
That's right,
we're all playing together.
Right, Noboru?
What are you saying?
No matter how you look at this,
it's bullying...
Onizuka-sensei!
Are you guys still doing
this kinda stuff?
Noboru, you're pathetic too!
- Help me, teacher!
- Let me join in.
What?
You guys, this is so half-assed!
This is so weak!
Teacher, aren't you going
to help me?
That's right?
What are you thinking?
Hey... I got a great idea.
Noboru, feels good,
doesn't it?
Onizuka-sensei,
what are you going to do?
- Teacher!
- How's that?
Help me!
Onizuka-sensei,
what are you doing!
- I'm scared!
- Woah, that was dangerous.
Stop this recklessness!
Stop it!
Ohh, that was close.
Oh geeze, how hopeless...
You know,
if you're going to do anything,
do it all the way.
That's my policy.
So Miyabi, what should I do?
If you tell me to, I'll drop him.
- Stop kidding around!
- What's that?
You said you were going
to kill this guy, right?
Hurry it up, my hand's slipping.
- We were kidding!
- He'll really die!
Please! Stop it!
You should have said
that sooner, stupid!
Okay, Noboru.
Noboru! Come on, get a grip!
This bullying ain't no fun
after all.
He doesn't put up any fight.
What's so fun about going
against such a weakling?
When you fight, it's more
interesting going up
against someone strong.
You think it's that great going
against this high schooler?
If you've got time to waste
on this, there's plenty
of other things you
could be doing!
Right?
Let me go!
How's that?
Please! Stop!
Onizuka! Do you think you
can get away with this!
Sure I do!
Of course I do!
So how do like this, Miyabi?
Isn't this great?
Isn't it great that the three of us
can eat out together as a family.
Isn't it, Yoshiko?
Give me a break.
Why did the onsen trip
become this?
I couldn't be helped, because
the Benz got wrecked...
I don't care about that.
And what happened to your
promise that you'd
- buy me a Prada bag?
- You see...
My salary's tied up
in repair bills.
That sucks!
You know, I canceled my trip
to the ocean with my
friends for this.
Give it up, Yoshiko.
We're not rich like that.
But!
I figured something was wrong
from the start anyway.
Your stingy Dad saying
all these things.
Listen, you shouldn't
trust your Dad.
I know, let's use my
secret savings
and go to Hawaii,
the two of us.
Really? Will you buy me
a Prada?
That Onizuka!
It's all his fault!
Onizuka!
Miyabe, are you okay?
So how'd you like it?
How's it feel to be bullied?
You're terrible!
Using violence on a girl!
Hey! When you're doing
something bad,
it doesn't matter if it's
a guy or girl.
My parents never scold me,
you know!
- Oh? And so?
- I'll remember this.
- We'll tell the head teacher!
- Him? Go ahead!
But don't ever lay
a finger on Noboru,
I'll kill whoever that does!
Alright Noboru, let's go.
Okay...
Fuyutsuki-sensei?
How hopeless...
Are you awake?
- Murderer!
- Huh? What?
You dropped Noboru
from the roof!
Hey, where's my beer?
- Here you go.
- Noboru-kun!
Then, what about
Aizawa Miyabi?
She's fine.
That's the first time
she's gotten it back.
You should have seen her face!
But I think you were
easy on her.
I wanted to see her
suffer more.
Don't get carried away.
Noboru, the one being bullied
isn't totally innocent.
To be taken for granted by
your opponent is the worst.
Show some compassion!
- I know.
- I don't think you do!
You jumped from some
place really high.
To kill yourself doesn't
take courage.
It takes more courage
to go on living!
Do you understand?
If you do, then go on home.
Go on!
Go on, Noboru.
Your parents must be worried.
Oh, geeze...
Looks like it's just
the two of us.
What?
It's late, do you want
to sleep here?
Don't be ridiculous! I'm going.
Then just stay a while.
I've been meaning
to tell you this,
your way of doing things
is too reckless.
Do you know how much
trouble you're
causing those around you?
What? Who?
Someone who just acts
on instincts without thinking,
shouldn't be a teacher!
Someone who puts on an act
at school shouldn't talk!
You're always grumbling,
but never say
anything to Uchiyamada.
Excuse me! Who asked you!
Who's the one who's always
at their beck and call?
I don't have a choice,
it's work!
Because it's work you should
tell them you don't like it!
Why don't you ever speak up?
You could never understand
what a woman
in the workplace goes through!
Women are expected to
do all those tasks!
Yeah?! Well you were about
to just let that
bullying go without doing
anything.
A man like you who resorts
to violence to solve everything
has no right to talk
to me like that!
- What?
- So what now?
Oh my! It's great seeing you
two getting along so well!
Onizuka-kun,
who would this be?
Could it be your girlfriend?
Don't be ridiculous!
I'm just a coworker.
- Will you turn that off!
- It can't be!
Do you mean you work with
such a marvelous woman?
Why so gallant now...
What do you mean?
I'm always like this!
Oh, excuse me,
I'm Saejima Ryûji.
I'm a friend, no, excuse me,
just an acquaintance
of Onizuka-kun.
I'm Fuyutsuki.
Excuse me.
- Oh! Let me see you out!
- No, I'm fine!
Oh no, it's my duty
as an officer!
Please wait!
Hold on a minute, teacher!
I really thought he killed
a student, my heart stopped!
Oh! This way!
These uncultured people.
In any case, it was totally
irresponsible!
I've never seen anyone
so dangerous!
Well, that's how he is.
I don't think he can
tolerate bullying.
What?
You see, he may have been
in a lot of fights,
but he's never picked
on anyone.
He's never used violence on
anyone weaker than him.
People who pick on the weak
are the scum of the earth,
that's how we felt.
Oh, um, I mean that's
how he felt.
Of course I wouldn't know
anything about that.
That's the first time in my life
I've ever been that scared!
He even threatened us!
He said he'd kill us all!
We can't come to school
with a violent
- homeroom teacher like that!
- We understand.
We're in a bind
with that Onizuka too.
I wonder what would happen if
my mother found out about this.
Miyabi's mother is
a commentator on a talk show,
I'm sure it'll cause a stir.
Please hold on!
Don't let it come to that!
We're looking to dismiss him.
- There's no reason for that.
- What do you mean?
We're tolerant people, we don't
want Onizuka-sensei fired.
- But instead...
- Instead?
At tomorrow's assembly,
we want Onizuka-sensei
- to kneel and apologize.
- What's that?
If he apologizes in front
of the entire student body,
then we'll forget all about it.
Are you serious?
If he does that, then you
won't tell your mother?
No fear! I'll show them!
What do you want?
- Um...
- What do you want, Noboru?
Onizuka-sensei did
nothing wrong.
What are you talking about?
Yesterday, he was only rescuing
me from Aizawa-san's bullying.
That's the truth!
Alright, come here...
I understand you wanting to help
your homeroom teacher,
but this is an administrative
affair.
It's true! Please believe me!
Then do you have proof
you've been bullied?
You took time off from school,
weren't you playing hooky?
I wasn't, I really...
You shouldn't blindly go
along with your friends.
Anyway, please feel free
to come to me any time.
We want to solve all problems.
Right? Now go on back
to class.
Aizawa-kun,
about your mother...
A kneeling apology?
That's just like you.
Rather than letting him just quit,
this is more interesting, isn't it?
You're right.
Kikuchi.
What do you think that
Onizuka's going to do?
Listen...
even if I quit school,
I'll still be with you...
We regret that this emergency
staff meeting had to be called.
Lately, there's been a teacher
who has thrown the morals
of school into disarray.
That person has caused
another unheard
of incident and we want
an apology.
This person.
This person has been involved
with many incidents
from the time he himself
was a student.
For instance,
being involved with gangs.
Dying his hair brown.
Or piercing his ears!
Stupid!
What's that snickering!
Who we're talking about,
is you, Onizuka-sensei!
Um... excuse me,
certainly, corporal punishment
is not good.
But...
I think there may be a problem
with the student, too.
- That's right!
- Stupid!
What kind of teacher would
lead a bullying?
I just wanted to show them
what it's like to be bullied!
Enough useless excuses!
I saw it myself!
That corporal punishment,
no it was attempted murder!
There's no way out of it!
There's no talking your
way out of it!
If you think I'm lying,
then talk to them!
You'll find out that it was Miyabi
who started bullying Noboru.
She says she doesn't
remember any of that.
Then are you saying you
don't believe Noboru?
Everyone, what do you think?
This certainly is a problem.
If you question
the persons bullying,
they'll just feign innocence.
If we inquire too much about it,
the parents'll come out
and say "There's no way
my children would do that",
and just make noise.
I think we should just leave it.
Trying to solve bullying is
too much for the teachers.
Do you think so? I think if you
take the time to properly
meet with each student,
you could solve the problem.
You're being too idealistic.
Besides if you do that,
you'll keep falling
behind your curriculum.
If the parents would properly
supervise their children,
it would solve
a lot of problems.
But then they try to push
it off onto the schools.
It is true that 2-4 is filled
with troublemaker students
hostile toward teachers.
Onizuka-sensei's actions
were understandable.
But to decide on the spot
that they were wrong
was a bad solution.
You couldn't really call it
a solution.
Instead of all this worthless
effort,
you should be more prudent,
Onizuka-sensei.
Well, in conclusion,
we will have Onizuka-sensei
take responsibility.
- What do you think?
- Hey wait!
Excuse me.
What is it, Fuyutsuki-sensei?
Yes... well...
It's nothing.
So, Onizuka-sensei.
Onizuka-sensei!
At tomorrow morning's
assembly,
please apologize
to Aizawa Miyabi.
But why should I?
What is that attitude?
We've come to this agreement.
If you kneel and apologize,
they said they will forgive
that incident!
If you are unwilling to do this,
then we'll have no choice
but to have you quit.
Do you understand?
What the hell?
- Hey there!
- Good morning!
Good morning!
Oh, what're you doing today?
I'll be saying farewell
to the students.
Oh, I see.
Oh, I heard a rumor.
Something about you
apologizing in front
of the students today.
Are you kidding?
Where'd you hear that?
Why are you always
so cheerful?
Because my policy is to always
be bright and cheerful!
That's not what I mean.
Oh, Noboru.
What's up?
Teacher, please!
What're you doing?
Please, apologize to everyone.
- What?
- Please!
Are you being serious?
Will you stop that!
If they fire you,
then they'll bully me
even more.
If that happens, then I won't
be able to go to school.
Please, teacher!
For today's assembly,
class 2-4's Aizawa Miyabi-kun,
has objected to her homeroom
teacher Onizuka-sensei's use
of corporal punishment.
This is an important issue
to this academy.
We have investigated this incident.
We have concluded that
Onizuka-sensei was in the wrong.
What Onizuka-sensei has
done is unforgivable.
If we leave it as is,
the relationship
between the teachers
and students will be harmed.
And so, in front
of the entire student body,
we will have Onizuka-sensei
apologize.
Onizuka-sensei.
What are you waiting for.
Um... excuse me.
Hold on, what are you doing,
Fujitomi-sensei?
- What are you doing?
- I'm sorry.
Um, everyone...
This is what I think.
There is no such thing as
a person without weapons.
Saying you are friends, when in
reality you don't trust them.
If you compare it to that,
there's the saying that
you fight because you're
such good friends.
Um, and so...
- Don't interfere!
- I'm sorry.
Onizuka-sensei.
- Kneel for us!
Kneel for us!
I'm sorry.
Noboru,
I can't do it after all.
Because I haven't done
anything wrong,
I can't apologize for that!
- Apologize!
- You promised!
- That's right!
- Apologize!
Shut up, Miyabi!
I'll tell you this, even if the entire
world told me you were correct,
I'd believe Noboru.
Why?
Because Noboru is my friend.
Right?
I'm Yoshikawa Noboru,
I'll show you my courage.
Hey! What are you doing!
Stop it!
These...
These are the injuries from
Aizawa Miyabi-san's bullying.
That's idiotic!
There's no proof that
we did that!
That's right, you probably
did it to yourself!
Head Teacher, what are you
going to do about this?
I'll have my mother file
a protest.
Look at this!
Noboru's got the guts
to come up here and do this!
Are you still saying
crap like that!
Noboru, what are you
scheming with Onizuka?
Well take good care
of you today!
Bullying you is the best way for
us to relieve stress, you know.
What should we do Miyabi,
this isn't good!
If you're going to be mad at us,
then you should be mad
at this school.
Because if there were something
else more interesting to do,
then we wouldn't
be bullying you like this.
But you know our teachers
are so clueless.
It's amazing that Uchiyamada's
the head teacher.
If I mention my mom,
he just withers.
- Turn that off!
- Stop it!
Turn it off! Who's doing that!
I see, so this is your doing.
Why did you do this?
Well, Noboru asked me to.
He wanted to get proof the next
time Aizawa bullied him.
That's why I had him keep
this hidden on him.
Although at one time I picked
on him too.
Why did you decide to help?
I didn't have a choice.
Because that Noboru said
he'd die if Onizuka left.
What?
To Noboru, Onizuka's...
his only friend.
WRITE REFLECTING
ON YOUR ACTIONS
You're good kids.
So what's happened
to Aizawa Miyabi?
Right now they're quietly writing
reflecting on their actions.
I think their feelings will change
a little after this,
I'll forgive them.
I'm glad.
Oh, we're you worried
about me?
What are you saying!
I didn't mean it that way!
What's with that defensive
attitude?
Aren't you misinterpreting
things?
- I'm always nice.
- Oh really?
And you're the one always
putting on a face.
That's why I was telling you
women face many difficulties!
Oh, are you going to
go off on that again?
Don't be so callous!
From now I'm going to be firm
with the head teacher
and Nakamaru, and give them
a piece of my mind.
Oh, you said it!
Don't forget you just said that.
A woman doesn't go back
on her word.
Oh, Fuyutsuki-sensei,
could you photocopy this.
Excuse me, I'm in a rush.
Okay, I understand.
- Fuyutsuki-sensei, tea please.
- Yes.
- Excuse me, some for me also.
Fujitomi-sensei,
what are you doing here?
Everything's been taken care of.
Go on home.
I've withdrawn my resignation
with the director.
What's that?
I intend to plant roots
at this academy!
Thank you.
W-W-Wait a minute!
I didn't hear a thing about this!
What should we do, sir?
That director!
Onizuka-sensei...
Yes?
This... is my policy.
Here's some tea.
Thank you.
- Well then, shall we go?
- Okay!
Shall we go another
round today?
Thanks for waiting!
I know it's hot today,
but let's work hard!
Did everyone go to the toilet?
2016-04